<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<root><context>http://schema.org/
</context><id>https://www.skillshare.com/classes/Convert-a-One-Page-HTML5-Template-to-a-WordPress-Theme/422143715undefined</id>undefined<name>Convert a One Page HTML5 Template to a WordPress Theme</name>undefined<description>Have you thought about creating a WordPress theme from a simple HTML5 template? In his 100-minute class, web developer Marcelo Vieira will guide you on how to convert a simple HTML5 template into a highly dynamic, fully functional WordPress theme.You will learn the basic techniques used for creating a WordPress theme. In the end, you'll be able to use the same techniques to convert your own HTML5 website into a fully functional theme.This course is not intended to be a definitive course on WordPress theme development, but it will be your first contact with the subject.This course has been carefully designed for professionals who already have minimal knowledge of HTML, CSS, PHP and wish to take a step forward in understanding how WordPress theme works.We will start from a simple one-page template, which will be transformed little by little into a WordPress theme. Along the way, you'll learn how to install WordPress in the right way, as well as the right way to transfer CSS and Javascript files from a template to a WordPress theme.We will learn to include Bootstrap and make the theme responsive, keeping the original features and the visual aspect of the HTML template within WordPress.And the most important! We will learn to make the template content highly dynamic within WordPress, from menus to text and image areas. I mean, you'll be able to create a theme that can be easily updated by you or your clients.We will also learn how to implement a fully dynamic post list by creating a custom WordPress loop!You'll also have access to all the files created during lessons. All of them well organized for you to review or correct your own code. At the end of the course, you will have learned how to create your own one-page theme, from any one-page HTML5 template, and confidently recreate a theme of your own. Are you ready? So, let's get started  </description>undefined<image>https://static.skillshare.com/uploads/video/thumbnails/ea13484477fe42d28a7daf03d20bcd9f/448-252</image>undefined<provider>
<name>Skillshare</name>
<sameAs>https://www.skillshare.com</sameAs>
<logo>https://static.skillshare.com/assets/images/hands_logo_2x.png</logo><type>Organizationundefined</type>undefined</provider>undefined<author>undefined<name>Marcelo Xavier Vieira</name>undefined<sameAs>https://www.skillshare.com/user/marcelovieira</sameAs>undefined<image>https://static.skillshare.com/uploads/users/2395183/user-image-medium.jpg?371597457</image><type>Personundefined</type>undefined</author><type>Courseundefined</type>undefined</root>